AMY CHEN

Seattle, WA | 206-688-0434 | <u>amychen.dev@gmail.com</u> | <u>www.amychen.dev</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/4myc</u> | Blog: <u>dev.to/4myc</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/4myc</u>

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Versatile front-end engineer with full-stack capability and a background in graphic and web design. Eager and quick learner keen on utilizing my creative and technical skills to create visually engaging user interfaces in order to improve user interaction and user experience. Enthusiastic about working on products that make an impact on users' lives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT-END

BACK-END

JavaScript

Rails

React.js

PostgreSQL

Ruby

RESTful APIs

HTML

Git

CSS

Material UI

Semantic UI

Bootstrap

DESIGN SKILLS

User Interface Design
Graphic Design
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe InDesign

EDUCATION

10/2019 - 03/2020

Flatiron School

Seattle, WA

Full Stack Web Development In-Person Program

06/2006 - 03/2010

The Art Institute of Seattle

Seattle, WA

BFA, Graphic Design

08/2005 - 05/2006

University of Central Arkansas

Conway, AR General Studies

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Trip Planner

GitHub Client | GitHub Server

Dynamic single-page app that allows a user to create trips and add a packing list and itinerary to each trip.

- + Collaborated with two team members and built the CRUD app within a 7-day timeline
- + Contributions: Trips page layout and design, new user form, toggle function to view a trip's edit forms, installed and set up Semantic UI, added back-end user validation
- + Utilized Semantic UI interactive elements to style Trips page user interface and improve user experience
- + Front-End: React.js, Semantic UI
- + Back-End: Rails, PostgreSQL

Leopardy! GitHub Repo

CLI trivia game about leopards inspired by Jeopardy! and Pup Quiz from The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon.

- + Full CRUD app built within a 4-day timeline
- + Implemented logic to allow the user to create, update, and delete an account
- + Implemented logic to create three multiple-choice game rounds
- + Incorporated ASCII logo and visual design elements to improve user experience
- + Technologies: Ruby, ActiveRecord

EXPERIENCE

Bookline Production Assistant Reischling Press Incorporated Tukwila, WA	11/2018 - 09/2019
Production Specialist & Graphic Designer content26 Seattle, WA	09/2010 - 04/2013
Customer Service Representative Minuteman Press Seattle, WA	10/2009 - 01/2010
Graphic Design Intern Washington CEO Magazine Seattle, WA	08/2008 - 09/2008
Graphic Design Intern Titan Seattle, WA	03/2008 - 08/2008